翻译    屈畅（ccxx）
校对    赵琳
狭海   The Narrow Sea
君临 King's Landing
时间轴    ren、antares
红堡
Red Keep
美术   cc、den、悠
鹰    巢    城     The     Eyrie
鹰
巢
城
The
Eyrie
鹰
巢
城
The
Eyrie
鹰
The
巢
Eyrie
鹰
The
城
Eyrie
巢
城
鹰
巢
城
The
Eyrie
咬人湾   The Bite
监制    临冬城的狮子
临冬城 Winterfell
后期   加文·维斯特林
人人网冰与火之歌公共主页
http://page.renren.com/601227719/index
后期   poplar
绝境长城 the Wall
压制   麻绳力攻
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
策划    baozhenyuawabi
龙堡字幕组  &  百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
维斯·多斯拉克
Vaes·Dothrak
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第一季 第七集
第七集  “不胜则死”
"You Win or You Die"
...即刻入朝为汝之封臣
"Summoned to court to answer for the crimes
“魔山”
of your bannerman Gregor Clegane,
格雷果·克里冈
the Mountain"...
所犯之暴行 承担罪责
Uh, "arrive within the fortnight
限期两周抵达 否则便是自承叛党
or be branded an enemy of the Crown."
可怜的奈德·史塔克
Poor Ned Stark...
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 西境守护 王后之父
有勇气 没脑子
Brave man, terrible judgment.
袭击他是件蠢事
Attacking him was stupid.
兰尼斯特家的人
Lannisters
不干蠢事
don't act like fools.
你觉得自己办得聪明？
Are you gonna say something clever?
说吧 你哪里聪明了？
Go on, say something clever.
凯特琳·史塔克抓了我弟弟
Catelyn Stark took my brother.
那他为什么还活着？
Why is he still alive?
- 提利昂？ - 奈德·史塔克
- Tyrion? - Ned Stark.
我正准备解决他...
One of our men interfered,
有个手下插手 刺穿了他的腿
speared him through the leg before I could finish him.
他为什么还活着？
Why is he still alive?
- 这样杀他不光彩 - 光彩？
- It wouldn't have been clean. - Clean.
你太在乎
You spend too much time worrying about
别人怎么看你了
what other people think of you.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
御林铁卫队长 王后的孪生弟弟 “弑君者”
我不在乎别人怎么看我
I could care less what anyone thinks of me.
你以为你做得到吗？
That's what you want people to think of you.
我就是这样的人
It's the truth.
也就是说你能接受
When you hear them whispering
别人在背后指指点点
"Kingslayer" behind your back--
叫你“弑君者”？
doesn't it bother you?
我不接受
Of course it bothers me.
为什么狮子要在意
The lion doesn't concern himself
绵羊的看法？
with the opinions of the sheep.
是不是我还得感谢你的虚荣
I suppose I should be grateful that your vanity
帮咱们家躲过一场冲动引发的灾祸？
got in the way of your recklessness.
这里有三万军队
I'm giving you half of our forces--
我拔一半给你
30,000 men.
我要你踏平凯特琳·徒利的娘家
You will bring them to Catelyn Stark's girlhood home
让她领教兰尼斯特
and remind her that Lannisters
有债必还
pay their debts.
想不到你挺在乎我弟弟的
I didn't realize you placed such a high value on my brother's life.
他是兰尼斯特家的人
He's a Lannister.
即便是最低贱的兰尼斯特 也是我们中的一员
He might be the lowest of the Lannisters, but he's one of us.
而对手每关押他一天
And every day that he remains a prisoner,
我们的威信就减弱一分
the less our name commands respect.
所以说狮子还是在意...
So the lion does concern himself with the opinions of--
不 这不是在意 这是我们昭告天下的公理：
No, it's not an opinion. It's a fact.
决不容忍任何家族冒犯我们之后
If another House can seize one of our own
能够全身而退
and hold him captive with impunity,
我们要让全天下畏惧
we are no longer a House to be feared.
你母亲已经去世
Your mother's dead.
我早晚也会离去
Before long I'll be dead.
甚至你
And you
你弟弟
and your brother and your sister
你姐姐和她所有的孩子
and all of her children. All of us dead;
终有一天也要尽归尘土
all of us rotting in the ground.
只有家族将永世长存
It's the family name that lives on.
繁衍不息
It's all that lives on.
你个人的荣耀 个人的得失在家族面前
Not your personal glory, not your honor,
都不值一提
but family.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
诸神让你生来武艺超群
You're blessed with abilities that few men possess.
诸神让你降生于七国中最强大的家族
You are blessed to belong to the most powerful family in the kingdoms.
而你现在还年轻
And you are still blessed with youth.
但你看看自己是怎么挥霍青春的 嗯？
And what have you done with these blessings, huh?
你自以为光鲜地去为两任国王当保镖...
You've served as a glorified bodyguard for two kings--
结果一个是疯子 一个是酒鬼
one a madman, the other a drunk.
现下家族兴衰在此一举
The future of our family will be determined in these next few months.
未来几个月 我们要么建立一个千年王朝...
We could establish a dynasty that will last a thousand years.
要么像坦格利安家一样灰飞烟灭
Or we could collapse into nothing, as the Targaryens did.
我要你挣开枷锁 肩负使命
I need you to become the man you were always meant to be.
不是明年 不是明天
Not next year. Not tomorrow.
现在
Now.
你的伤没好
You're in pain.
我受过更重的伤 陛下
I've had worse, My Lady.
或许你该回家去
Perhaps it's time to go home.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
王后
南方不是你该待的地方
The South doesn't seem to agree with you.
艾德·史塔克
御前首相 临冬城公爵 昵称“奈德”
我知道琼恩·艾林是为什么死的
I know the truth Jon Arryn died for.
是吗？史塔克大人
Do you, Lord Stark?
你就为这把我叫来？跟我猜谜语？
Is that why you called me here, to pose me riddles?
他打过你吗？
Has he done this before?
詹姆会跟他拼命
Jaime would have killed him.
我弟弟胜过你朋友一千倍
My brother is worth a thousand of your friend.
你弟弟...
Your brother...
还是你爱人？
Or your lover?
坦格利安家三百年来都是兄妹通婚
The Targaryens wed brothers and sisters for 300 years
以保持血统纯正
to keep bloodlines pure.
詹姆和我不只是姐弟
Jaime and I are more than brother and sister.
我俩共享同一子宫
We shared a womb.
一起降世 我俩属于彼此
We came into this world together. We belong together.
我儿子看见你跟他在一起
My son saw you with him.
你很爱你的孩子 对不对？
Do you love your children?
- 全心全意 - 我也是这么爱着自己的孩子
- With all my heart. - No more than I love mine.
- 都是詹姆的孩子 - 感谢天上诸神
- And they are all Jaime's. - Thank the Gods.
即便劳勃偶尔能远离那些婊子
In the rare event that Robert leaves his whores
喝完酒跌跌撞撞地找到我的床
for long enough to stumble drunk into my bed,
我也有其他方法满足他
I finish him off in other ways.
- 反正第二天早上他就会忘得一干二净 - 你一直恨着他
- In the morning, he doesn't remember. - You've always hated him.
恨着他？我仰慕他
Hated him? I worshipped him.
他是当年七国每个女孩的梦中情人
Every girl in the Seven Kingdoms dreamed of him,
而他发了婚誓 他属于我
but he was mine by oath.
婚礼当天
And when I finally saw him
我们一同步入贝勒大圣堂
on our wedding day in the Sept of Baelor,
看见他黑须髯髯 精壮勇武的样子
lean and fierce and black-bearded,
那是我一生中最幸福的时刻
it was the happiest moment of my life.
可那天晚上他压在我身上 浑身酒臭
Then that night he crawled on top of me, stinking of wine
办那一丁点儿事...真的是一丁点儿事的时候
and did what he did-- what little he could do--
他在我耳边悄悄念道“莱安娜”
and whispered in my ear, "Lyanna."
你妹妹尸骨已寒 我却是活生生的女子
Your sister was a corpse and I was a living girl
他却依然爱她不爱我
and he loved her more than me.
等国王打猎归来 我准备把事情原原本本地告诉他
When the King returns from his hunt, I'll tell him the truth.
在这之前你一定得走...带着孩子一起
You must be gone by then-- you and your children.
我不愿沾上他们的鲜血
I will not have their blood on my hands.
你能跑多远就跑多远
Go as far away as you can,
能带多少人就带少人
with as many men as you can.
因为即便你逃到天涯海角
Because wherever you go,
劳勃的怒火也会尾随而至
Robert's wrath will follow you.
那我的怒火又怎么说 史塔克大人？
And what of my wrath, Lord Stark?
当初你只需伸手便可夺取天下
You should have taken the realm for yourself.
詹姆跟我说过 君临城陷那天
Jaime told me about the day King's Landing fell.
你发现他坐在铁王座上 便要求他交出王位
He was sitting in the Iron Throne and you made him give it up.
你当时为什么不爬上阶梯？
All you needed to do was climb the steps yourself.
这是个可悲的错误
Such a sad mistake.
我这辈子犯过许多错
I've made many mistakes in my life,
这却不是其中之一
but that wasn't one of them.
噢 这当然是
Oh, but it was.
在权力的游戏之中 你不当赢家
When you play the Game of Thrones, you win
就只有死路一条
or you die.
没有中间地带
There is no middle ground.
不对 不对 不对 不对
No no no no!
北方的老板就是这样调教你的吗？
Is that what they teach you up in the North?
还有你 不管你是打哪儿来的
And you-- wherever you're from,
知不知道你叫得多滑稽？
do you have any idea how ridiculous you sound?
你们是不是听不明白我的话？
Either of you understand a thing that I'm saying?
罗丝
妓女
明白 大人
Yes, My Lord.
那就重来
Let's start over, shall we?
这回你当男
You be the man
她扮女
and you be the woman.
就这样 开始吧
Well, go ahead.
慢点儿
Slowly.
别当客人是傻瓜 他们为你付过钱
You're not fooling them. They just paid you.
他们知道你是什么货色
They know what you are.
他们知道一切都是逢场作戏
They know it's all just an act.
你的任务是要让他们忘掉这些
Your job is to make them forget what they know.
而这需要反复操练
That takes time.
你一定要...
You need to...
投入
Ease into it.
培提尔·贝里席
财政大臣 “小指头”
就是这样
Go ahead.
投入
Ease into it.
你不只是装模作样
He's winning you over in spite of yourself.
你确实让他觉得很爽
You're starting to like this.
他渴望你的表演
He wants to believe you.
自从他懂得自娱自乐起 他就宠着他那话儿
He's enjoyed his cock since he was old enough to play with it.
不是吗？ 他自信比别的男人强
Why shouldn't you? He knows he's better than other men.
现在他有了证据
He's always known it deep down inside. Now he has proof.
他太伟岸了
He's so good,
只有他能进到你的深处
he's reaching something deep inside of you that
无人开发过的地方
no one even knew was there,
释放出你的全部欲望
overcoming your very nature.
你干嘛不来亲自教我们呢 大人？
Why don't you join us, My Lord?
我心里念着一个女人
I'm saving myself for another.
没关系 她又不知道这里的事儿
What she doesn't know won't hurt her.
这是蠢话
A stupid saying.
我们不知道的事往往会引来杀身之祸
What we don't know is usually what gets us killed.
她一定有倾国倾城的容貌喽？
She must be very beautiful.
倒也不是 只是血统绝对高贵无暇
No, not really. Impeccable bloodlines though.
大人您真的谈恋爱了啊
I do believe My Lord's in love.
我爱了她很多年 可以说大半辈子
For many years. Most of my life really.
都跟在她屁股后面
Play with her ass.
她也喜欢我
And she loved me too.
她把我当成小跟班
I was her little confidant,
小玩伴
her plaything.
她对我畅所欲言 无话不谈
She could tell me anything, anything at all.
她告诉我 她喜欢哪些马
She told me about all the horses that she liked,
憧憬哪些城堡
the castle she wanted to live in and the man
还有她想嫁给谁
that she wanted to marry.
那是一个北方佬 生着一个铁砧模样的下巴
A northerner with a jaw like an anvil.
知道这个消息后 我找他决斗
So I challenged him to a duel.
为什么不呢？故事里不都这样写着么？
I mean, why not? I'd read all the stories.
在故事里 小英雄总能打败大坏蛋
The little hero always beats the big villain in all the stories.
但在我的故事里 结局是她央求他不要杀我
In the end, she wouldn't even let him kill me.
她说“他只是个孩子”
"He's just a boy," she said.
“请别伤害他”
"Please don't hurt him."
于是他只在我身上留了一道小疤作纪念
So he gave me a nice little scar to remember him by
- 便带她扬长而去 - 他们后来结婚了？
- and off they went. - Is she still married to him?
噢 很不幸
Oh no.
卤莽让他在结婚前就送了命
He got himself killed before the wedding...
她跟了他弟弟
..And she ended up with his brother,
一个更严肃的道德楷模
an even more impressive specimen.
似乎她还日久生情了
She loves him, I'm afraid.
谁能怪她呢？谁能跟他比呢？
And why wouldn't she? I mean, who could compare to him?
他简直是...
He's just so...
完美
Good.
你知道输掉决斗让我明白了什么吗？
Do you know what I learned, losing that duel?
我明白了那是他们的游戏
I learned that I'll never win,
按照他们的规则
not that way. That's their game,
我永远也赢不了
their rules.
我不会再找他们决斗了
I'm not going to fight them.
我要在自己的地盘 用自己的方式
I'm going to fuck them. That's what I know.
搞垮他们
That's what I am.
只有看清了自己 才能得到自己想要的东西
And only by admitting what we are can we get what we want.
您想要什么？
And what do you want?
噢 一切 亲爱的
Oh, everything, my dear.
所有的一切
Everything there is.
现在去洗干净 你两个今晚都要接客
Now wash yourselves. Both of you are working tonight.
知道么 你是个幸运的女孩
You're a very lucky girl. Do you know that?
在我故乡 我们对罪犯从不心慈手软
Where I come from, we don't show mercy to criminals.
在我故乡 你这路货色若是敢抢劫小少爷
Where I come from, if someone like you attacked a little lord?
欧莎
女野人
会在退潮时被仰面栓在沙滩上
At low tide we'd lay you on your back on the beach,
席恩·葛雷乔伊
临冬城公爵养子
用木桩和铁链固定住四肢
your hands and feet chained to four stakes.
潮水会一点点地涨上来
The sea would come in closer and closer.
每分每秒 死神一寸一寸地逼近...
You'd see death creeping toward you a few inches at a time.
你的故乡是哪儿啊？
Where is it you come from?
铁群岛
The Iron Islands.
离这儿远吗？
They far away?
怎么？你没听说过铁群岛？
You've never heard of the Iron Islands?
相信我 你也没听说过我的故乡
Trust me, you've never heard where I'm from neither.
相信我 “大人”
"Trust me, My Lord."
这里不是没开化的蛮夷之地
You're not living in the wilderness anymore.
在文明人的国度
In civilized lands, you refer to your betters
你得学会用适当的称号来称呼老爷们
by their proper titles.
- 什么称号？ - 大人
- And what's that? - Lord.
为什么？
Why?
这还不明显吗？
What do you mean why?
我父亲是巴隆·葛雷乔伊 铁群岛的大王
My father is Balon Greyjoy, Lord of the Iron Islands.
那跟你有啥关系？
What's that got to do with you?
你父亲是大王
If your father's lord,
所以你当自己也是大王？
how can you be lord too?
我会继承父亲的权位...
I will be lord after my father--
所以你现在还不是大王嘛
so you're not lord now?
你 你...
No, you--
你故意跟我作对 是不是？
You having a go at me? Is that it?
我只是闹不明白你们南方人咋想的罢了
I just don't understand how you Southerners do things.
- 我不是南方人 - 你住在长城以南
- I'm not a Southerner. - You're from South of the wall.
对我来说你就是南方人
That makes you a Southerner to me.
你这放肆的小婊子
You're an impudent little wench, aren't you?
不明白啊 大人
Couldn't say, My Lord.
闹不明白“放肆”这个词是啥意思
Don't know what "impunent" means.
放肆 就是粗鲁
Impudent. It means rude,
没礼貌
disrespectful.
你想不想除掉镣铐？
Do you want to lose that chain?
席恩·葛雷乔伊！
Theon Greyjoy!
这位女士是我们的客人
The lady is our guest.
我以为她是我们的俘虏
I thought she was our prisoner.
鲁温
临冬城学士
怎么 这两者矛盾吗？
Are the two mutually exclusive in your experience?
再发生这种事 我就不一定在场了
Chances are I won't be nearby the next time that happens.
我见过的混蛋多的是
I'm used to worse than him.
他这样的毛头小子要落在那帮混蛋手里
I'm used to men who could chew that boy up
准教被一口吞下 还拿他的骨头剔牙
and pick their teeth with his bones.
你来此是要做什么？
Why did you come here?
我压根儿不想来这里
Didn't mean to come here.
我们打算一路逃往南方
Meant to get much further South than this.
越往南越好
As far South as South goes,
赶在长夜降临之前
before the long night comes.
为什么？你们在害怕什么？
Why? What are you afraid of?
昼伏夜出的东西
There's things that sleep in the day and hunt at night.
也就是猫头鹰 影子山猫和...
Owls and Shadowcats and--
我指的不是猫头鹰和影子山猫
I'm not talking about Owls and Shadowcats.
你暗示的那些
The "things" you speak of--
几千年前就消失了
they've been gone for thousands of years.
他们没有消失 老头
They wasn't gone, old man.
只是在沉睡
They was sleeping.
而现在他们醒了
And they ain't sleeping no more.
我想姑娘
I miss girls.
其实我没跟她们说过话 说不来话
Not even talking to them. I never talked to them.
山姆威尔·塔利
守夜人
看着就好
Just looking at them,
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人 临冬城公爵的私生子
还能听她们嘻笑
hearing them giggle.
你就不想姑娘吗？
Don't you miss girls?
骑手！
Riders.
吹号 咱们得去吹号
The horn. We have to blow the horn.
怎么就一个人？
Why is he alone?
一声号角代表兄弟归来
One blast for a Ranger returning,
两声代表野人逼近
two for Wildlings,
- 三声... - 只有一匹马
- three for-- - there's no rider.
这是我班扬叔叔的马
That's my Uncle Benjen's horse.
我叔叔哪儿去了？
Where's my Uncle?
杰奥·莫尔蒙
守夜人总司令
奈德！
Ned!
劳勃他...我们当时...
It's Robert. We were hunting--
蓝礼·拜拉席恩
风息堡公爵 国王幼弟
在猎野猪...
a boar--
我应该多陪着你
I should have spent more time with you,
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
大王子
教导你如何成为男子汉
shown you how to be a man.
劳勃·拜拉席恩
国王
我不是个好父亲
I was never meant to be a father.
出去吧...
Go on.
你没必要看下去
You don't want to see this.
派席尔
大学士
我自己失误...
My fault.
酒喝多了 结果没射中
Too much wine, missed my thrust.
臭死了
It stinks.
这就是死亡的臭气
It stinks like death.
别以为我闻不出来
Don't think I can't smell it.
我也没让那王八蛋好过 奈德
I paid the bastard back, Ned.
我一刀捅进它脑子里
I drove my knife right through his brain.
你问问他们是不是真的...问哪！
You ask them if I didn't. Ask them!
我要我的葬礼宴会成为
I want the funeral feast to be the biggest
七国有史以来最风光的
the Kingdoms ever saw.
我要让所有人都尝尝这头干掉我的野猪
And I want everyone to taste the boar that got me.
你们都退下 我跟奈德谈谈
Now leave us, the lot of you. I need to talk to Ned.
劳勃 亲爱的... - 退下！都退下！
- Robert, my sweet-- - Out, all of you!
你太傻了
You damned fool.
拿纸笔来 就在那边桌上
Paper and ink on the table,
把我说的写下：
write down what I say.
吾 拜拉席恩家族的
"In the name of Robert of the House Baratheon,
劳勃一世...把他妈那些鬼头衔通通放进去
first of--" you know how it goes.
你知道是哪些
Fill in the damn titles.
在此任命...
"I hereby command
史塔克家族的艾德...
Eddard of House Stark--"
头衔...头衔...
titles, titles--
为摄政王及全境守护者
"to serve as Lord Regent and Protector of the Realm
自吾死后...
upon my death,
...代吾统理国事
to rule in my stead
俟吾儿乔佛里成年
until my son Joffrey comes of age."
（奈德改为“俟吾之合法继承人成年”）
拿过来
Give it over.
等我死了
Give it to the council
把这个交给御前会议
after I'm dead.
至少 人们会说我这辈子做的最后一件事
At least they'll say I did this right,
没有错
this one thing.
国家就交给你了
You'll rule now.
你会比我更讨厌治理...
You'll hate it worse than I did,
但你会做得很好
but you'll do it well.
那女孩...
The girl--
丹妮莉丝...
Daenerys.
你说得没错 瓦里斯 小指头
You were right. Varys, Littlefinger,
我弟弟...废物们...
my brother... Worthless.
除了你 没人敢对我说一个“不”字
No one to tell me "no" but you.
除了你
Only you.
让她活命罢
Let her live.
阻止他们...如果还来得及
Stop it, if it's not too late.
我会的
I will.
还有我儿子...
And my son...
帮帮他 奈德
Help him, Ned.
让他变成比我更好的人
Make him better than me.
我...
I'll...
为了你 我会尽我所能
I'll do everything I can to honor your memory.
为了我？
My memory.
为了这个被猪拱死的国王
King Robert Baratheon,
劳勃·拜拉席恩？
murdered by a pig.
给我止痛的东西 让我去死罢
Give me something for the pain and let me die.
给他罂粟花奶
Give him milk of the poppy.
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
御林铁卫队长
陛下醉得站都站不稳
He was reeling from the wine.
还是命令我们...
He commanded us
站一边去
to step aside, but...
我辜负了他
I failed him.
谁也没法阻止国王伤害自己
No man could have protected him from himself.
巴利斯坦爵士 我倒是很好奇
I wonder, Ser Barristan,
这酒是谁拿给国王的？
who gave the king this wine?
他的侍从 拿的是国王自己的酒袋
His squire, from the king's own skin.
他的侍从？那兰尼斯特小子？
His squire? The Lannister boy?
真是个忠于职守的好孩子
Such a dutiful boy to make sure his Grace
瓦里斯
太监 情报总管 “八爪蜘蛛”
陛下他永远都不愁没得喝哟
did not lack refreshment.
真希望这可怜的孩子别太自责
I do hope the poor lad does not blame himself.
关于丹妮莉丝·坦格利安那件事
His Grace has had a change of heart
劳勃已经回心转意
concerning Daenerys Targaryen.
无论你安排了什么...
Whatever arrangements you made,
我要你立刻收回成命
unmake them. At once.
恐怕
I'm afraid
鸟儿已经飞上了天
those birds have flown.
这女孩已经死了哪
The girl is likely dead already.
Vezh fin saja rhaesheseres vo zigereo adoroon shiqethi.
骑着世界的骏马不需要铁椅子
The stallion that mounts the world has no need for iron chairs.
K'asi assikhqoyisiri
预言所载
According to the prophecy
vezh adothrae nakhaan rhaesheseri.
骏马将行至世界尽头
the stallion will ride to the ends of the world.
Sorfosor nakha she Havazzhifi Kazga.
世界的尽头是黑色咸海
The earth ends at The Black Salt Sea.
Vo hrazef laz yoma evethiz.
没有马可以穿越毒水
No horse can cross the poison water.
Sorfosor nakho vosecchi.
那里不是世界尽头
The Earth never ends.
Sani sorfi vekha yomme.
在海的另一边 有一片广袤的泥土
There are many dirts across.
Sorfo athyolari anni.
我出生的泥土
The dirts of my birth.
Vo sorfo. Rhaeshi.
不是泥土 是土地
Not dirt. Lands.
Rhaeshi, sek
土地 是的...
Lands, yes.
卓戈 卡奥
多斯拉克部族首领
Dalen rhaggati evetha ma ale
自由贸易城邦有几千艘船
There are thousands of ships
ido fini ovethi yomme
它们就是能够横越海洋的木马
Wooden that fly across
Kisha vastoki vos alikh hrazefi ido m'adori shiqethi.
我们不要再谈木马和铁椅子
Let's speak no more about wooden horses or iron chairs.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
卡丽熙
Me vos ador.Me...me...
那不是椅子 是
It's not a chair. It's...it's...
王座
...Throne.
Throne.
Ador finaan khal nevasoe...
那是卡奥的王座
A chair for a king to sit upon...
che khaleesi.
或者是卡丽熙的
or a queen.
Khal vos zigereo adoroon anevasoe maan.
卡奥不需要椅子
A khal doesn't need a chair to sit on.
Me zigeree sajosoon disse.
他只需要一匹骏马
He only needs a steed.
你就不能帮助我让他了解吗？
Can't you help me make him understand?
多斯拉克人行事自有其步调和理由
The Dothraki do things in their own time, for their own reasons.
卡丽熙 请您耐心等待 我们会回家的 我向您保证
Have patience, Khaleesi. We will go home, I promise you.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
杰奥·莫尔蒙之子
我哥...是个傻瓜 我知道
My brother was a fool, I know,
可他毕竟是七大王国的合法继承人
but he was the rightful heir to the Seven Kingdoms.
我说得不对吗 爵士先生？
Have I said something funny, Ser?
请原谅 卡丽熙 但您的先祖...吞并六国的“征服者”伊耿
Forgive me, Khaleesi, but your ancestor Aegon the Conqueror
他可不管什么合法不合法
didn't seize six of the kingdoms because they were his right.
他对维斯特洛没有任何权利 他靠的是武力
He had no right to them. He seized them because he could.
靠的是龙
And because he had dragons.
是啊 天上掉下几条龙事情就简单多了
Ah well, having a few dragons makes things easier.
- 你不相信有龙吗？ - 敢问您见过龙吗 卡丽熙？
- You don't believe it. - Have you ever seen a dragon, Khaleesi?
所谓眼见为实
I believe what my eyes and ears report.
三百年前的事
As for the rest... It was 300 years ago.
谁知道真相如何？
Who knows what really happened?
请容我暂时告退 我要去找商队统领
Now if you'll pardon me, I'll seek out the merchant Captain,
看看有没有给我的信
see if he has any letters for me.
- 好啊 我帮你找 - 不 不 不必劳动您
- I'll come with you. - No no, don't trouble yourself.
尽情享受这市集吧 我快去快回
Enjoy the market. I'll rejoin you soon enough.
嗨 安答尔人乔拉
Psst, Jorah the Andal.
蜘蛛让我带来问候
The spider sends his greetings
和祝贺
and his congratulations.
你获得了王家赦免...可以回家了
A royal pardon-- you can go home now.
Virzetha gizikhven!Mra qora!Mra qora!
香甜的红酒啰
Sweet reds. I have it. I have it.
Virzetha gizikhven!Virzethi gizikhven vekha m'anhoon, Lysoon, Volantisoon, ma Halahisiroon.
我有里斯 瓦兰提斯和青亭岛产的香甜红酒！
Sweet reds! I have sweet reds from Lys, Volantis and the Arbor.
Sovikh Tirosh!Jelavena Andahloa.
泰洛西产的梨子白兰地 安达尔酸酒！
Tyroshi pear brandy. Andhalish sours!
Mra qora!Mra qora!
我通通都有！通通都有啰！
I have them! I have them!
Lekhi ha khaleesisaan?
卡丽熙 您要不要尝一口？
A taste for the khaleesi?
M'anhoon vekha virzethi gizkhvena Dornoon, zhey erinak.
尊贵的夫人 我有多恩产的夏日红酒
I have a sweet red from Dorne, my lady.
At lekhi ma shafka ahakee yal hakesoon anni.
您只需喝上一口 保证会用我的名字为孩子命名
One taste and you'll name your first child after me.
我儿子已经有名字了
My son already has his name,
不过我还是尝尝你的夏日红吧 一口就好
but I'll try your summerwine.Just a taste.
尊贵的夫人 您是维斯特洛人吗？
My Lady, you are from Westeros.
多莉亚
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
你有幸与马上民族的卡丽熙 七大王国的公主
You have the honor of addressing Daenerys of the House Targaryen,
坦格利安家族的丹妮莉丝说话
Khaleesi of the riding men and princess of the Seven Kingdoms.
- 公主殿下 - 起来吧
- Princess. - Rise.
我还想尝尝你的夏日红呢
I'd still like to taste that wine.
这个？这是多恩的猪饲料
That? Dornish swill.
配不上公主您的
Not worthy of a princess.
我有一种青亭岛产的干红
I have a dry red from the Arbor--
堪称诸神的花蜜
nectar of the Gods.
让我送您一桶罢 作为礼物！
Let me give you a cask. Uh-- a gift.
您太客气了 先生
You honor me, Ser.
这...这应该说是我的荣幸
The honor-- the honor is all mine.
公主殿下您知道吗？在您的故国 子民们日夜祈祷您的归来呢
There are many in your homeland that pray for your return, princess.
我希望将来能回报你的好意
I hope to repay your kindness someday.
拉卡洛
Rakharo.
azzohi haz khogare.
把酒放下
put down that cask.
拉卡洛
血盟卫
- 有什么不对吗？ - 我口正渴
- Is something wrong? - I have a thirst.
把酒打开
Open it.
酒是要送给卡丽熙 不是给你这种人喝的
The wine is for the Khaleesi. It's not for the likes of you.
打开
Open it.
倒酒
Pour.
这么好的酒 不让它先透透气就喝
It would be a crime to drink a wine this rich
简直是滔天大罪啊
without at least giving it time to breathe.
照他说的做
Do as he says.
谨遵公主殿下吩咐
As the princess commands.
很香吧？
Sweet, isn't it?
爵士先生 您可闻出了葡萄的香气？
Can you smell the fruit, Ser?
就请您先尝尝 大人
Taste it, My Lord.
然后告诉我
Tell me that that is not the finest wine
这是不是您喝过的最甘甜的酒
that has ever touched your tongue.
你先喝
You first.
我？
Me?
我不够格喝这么好的酒
I'm afraid I am not worthy of the vintage.
何况哪有酒贩子
Besides, it is a poor wine merchant who would
喝自己的酒呢？
drink up his own wares.
叫你喝你就喝
You will drink.
- 卡丽熙！ - 抓住他！
- Khaleesi! - Stop him!
走吧
Come.
你们来时为法律所不容
You came to us as outlaws,
盗猎 强奸
poachers, rapers,
杀人 偷窃
killers, thieves.
你们来时孑然一身 身负枷锁
You came alone, in chains,
既无友朋
without friends
更无荣誉
nor honor.
你们来时或富贵荣禄 或赤贫如洗
You came to us rich and you came to us poor.
你们来自豪门望族
Some of you bear the names of proud houses,
或仅有私生子之名 甚或籍籍无名
others only bastard names or no names at all.
但这些都不重要
It does not matter.
一切已成过去
All that is in the past.
在这里
Here,
长城之上
on the wall,
我们都是一家人
are all one house.
- 今晚... - 开心点儿
- Tonight... - You're allowed to look happy.
你就快当上游骑兵了
You're going to be a Ranger.
你不老想着这个么？
Isn't that what you always wanted?
我只想找到我叔叔
I want to find my Uncle.
我知道他还活着
I know he's alive out there.
就在长城外面
I know he is.
我倒是想帮你 可惜我不是游骑兵
I wish I could help you, but I'm no Ranger.
我注定只能作事务官
It's the steward's life for me.
当事务官也是种荣誉
There's honor in being a steward.
荣誉谈不上
Not much, really.
但可以放开肚皮吃
But there's food.
你们将于兹重获新生
Here you begin anew.
守夜人的汉子
A man of The Night's Watch...
为王国效命
Lives his life for the realm.
非为国王
Not for a king,
非为贵族
or a lord,
亦非为豪门荣辱
or the honor of this house or that house;
不论财富 不论光荣
not for gold nor glory
亦不论儿女情爱
nor a woman's love;
一切只为王国安泰
but for the realm
及其子民平安
and all the people in it.
你们都听过了誓言内容
You've all learned the words of the vow.
在发誓以前请仔细考虑
Think carefully before you say them.
背离职守
The penalty for desertion
将只有死刑
is death.
你们可以在此发誓
You can take your vows here
等到今夜 日落时分
tonight at sunset.
你们中还有信仰旧神的吗？
Do any of you still keep the old Gods?
有的 大人
I do, My Lord.
你情愿跟你叔叔一样 在心树之下宣誓？
You'll want to take your vow before a heart tree as your Uncle did.
是的 大人
Yes, My Lord.
你会在长城以北一里处找到一片鱼梁木
You'll find a Weirwood a mile North of the Wall.
或许也会找到你的旧神
And your old Gods too, maybe.
大人？我能不能跟他一起去？
My Lord, might I go as well?
塔利家族莫非信奉旧神？
Does house Tarly keep the old Gods?
不是的 大人
No, My Lord.
我的命名仪式乃是在七神的荣光照耀下举行
I was named in the light of the Seven,
我父亲如此 他的父亲亦如此
as my father was and his father before him.
那你为何要抛弃令尊和你家族长久以来信仰的诸神呢？
Why would you forsake the Gods of your father and your house?
如今我以守夜人军团为家
The Night's Watch is my house now.
七神从未回应我的祈祷
The Seven have never answered my prayers.
或许旧神会呢
Perhaps the old Gods will.
那就这样 小子
As you wish, lad.
依照我们的需求
You've all been assigned an order,
以及你们自身的能力
according to our needs
你们将被分配到不同的职业
and your strengths.
霍德 加入工匠
Halder to the builders.
派普 加入事务官
Pyp to the stewards.
陶德 加入工匠 葛兰 加入游骑兵
Toad to the builders. Grenn to the Rangers.
山姆威尔 加入事务官
Samwell to the stewards.
梅沙 加入游骑兵 戴利恩 加入事务官
Matthar to the Rangers. Dareon to the stewards.
巴连 加入游骑兵
Balian to the Rangers.
雷斯特 加入游骑兵
Rast to the Rangers.
琼恩 加入事务官
Jon to the stewards.
雷瑟 加入工匠
Rancer to the builders.
伊策 加入工匠
Echiel to the builders.
加多 加入事务官
Gordo to the stewards.
尼可 加入游骑兵 伊坎 加入游骑兵
Niko to the Rangers. Escan to the Rangers.
艾里沙·索恩
黑城堡的守夜人教头
沃科 加入工匠 乔比 去马厩
Vorkoy to the builders. Joby to the stables.
明克 去厨房 阿洛 加入工匠
Mink to the kitchens. Allo to the builders.
内罗戈 加入游骑兵
Nelugo to the Rangers.
愿天上诸神眷顾你们
May all the Gods preserve you.
游骑兵跟我来
Rangers with me.
工匠！
Builders!
伊蒙·坦格利安
守夜人的学士
山姆威尔 你帮我管理鸟笼和图书室
Samwell, you will assist me in the rookery and library.
派普 你去厨房向波文·马尔锡报道
Pyp, you will report to Bowen Marsh in the kitchens.
卢克 你去马厩向独眼乔报道
Luke, report to one-eyed Joe in the stables.
戴利恩 我们派你去东海望
Dareon, we are sending you to Eastwatch.
你到了之后找波卡斯
Present yourself to Borcas when you arrive.
记得别取笑他的鼻子
Make no comment about his nose.
琼恩·雪诺 莫尔蒙司令
Jon Snow, Lord Commander Mormont
要你当他的私人事务官
has requested you for his personal steward.
我是不是要帮总司令打理三餐？
Will I serve the Lord Commander's meals
为他打热水洗澡？
and fetch hot water for his bath.
没有错
Certainly.
你还要为他房间生火
And keep a fire burning in his chambers,
每天为他换洗床单和毛毯
change his sheets and blankets daily
以及承担总司令要你做的任何其他事情
and do everything else the Lord Commander requires of you.
你当我是下人么？
Do you take me for a servant?
我们当你是守夜人的汉子
We took you for a man of The Night's Watch.
不过或许我们错看了你
But perhaps we were wrong in that.
- 我可以走了吗？ - 去吧
- May I go? - As you wish.
琼恩 等等！
Jon, wait!
你看不出他们的用意吗？
Don't you see what they're doing?
我只看出这是艾里沙爵士的报复
I see Ser Alliser's revenge, that's all.
他想羞辱我 这下得遂心愿了
He wanted it and he got it.
事物官和女仆没两样！
Stewards are nothing but maids!
不论使剑 骑马我都比你们行！
I'm a better swordsman and rider than any of you!
- 这太不公平了！ - 公平？
- It's not fair. - Fair?
我以前为橡果厅的领主唱歌时
I was singing for a high lord at Acorn Hall
派普尔
守夜人 亦称“派普”
他把手伸到我两腿之间 说要瞧瞧我的命根子
when he put his hand on my leg and he wanted to see my cock.
我把他推开 他竟然宣布
I pushed him away and he said he'd have my hands cut off
要以偷窃罪砍我的手
for stealing their silver.
我就这样被发配到了这里 到了世界的尽头
So now I'm here-- at the end of the world
从此只能给老头子
with no one to sing for
和你们这样的小杂毛唱歌
but old men and little shits like you.
再不能跟家人见面
I'll never see my family again.
再不能跟女人亲热
I'll never be inside a woman again.
别告诉我什么叫公平
So don't tell me about fair.
我还以为你是为挨饿的老妹
I thought you were caught stealing a wheel of cheese
偷了一轮奶酪才被抓的
for your starving sister?
谁会随便跟一群陌生人吐露
You think I was gonna tell a bunch of strangers
一个高高在上的老爷看上了他的命根子？
that a high lord tried to grab my cock?
能唱首歌吗 派普？我想听歌
Could you sing me a song, Pyp? I'd like to hear a song.
现在听我说
Now listen to me.
你要伺候的老头可是堂堂守夜人军团总司令
The old man is the Lord Commander of The Night's Watch.
而你会日夜跟他相处
You'll be with him day and night.
没错 你是得帮他洗衣服
Yes, you'll clean his clothes.
但你也会替他送信 随他参加会议
But you'll also take his letters, attend him at meetings,
打仗的时候当他的侍从
squire for him in battle.
大小事务你都会知情 甚至能施加影响
You'll know everything, be part of everything.
更何况是他指定要你的...
And he asked for you himself.
他是想训练你作接班人哪
He wants to groom you for command.
我只是...
I just...
我一直想当个游骑兵
I always wanted to be a Ranger.
我还一直想当魔法师呢
I always wanted to be a Wizard.
怎么了？
What?
别笑 我是认真的
No, I'm serious.
你会留下来跟我一起宣誓？
So you'll stay and say your words with me?
艾德大人 借一步说话？
Lord Stark, a moment.
请您的人退下
Alone if you will.
他任命您为全境守护者？
He named you Protector of the Realm.
是的
He did.
那个女人不会在意的
She won't care.
给我一个钟头 我能给您一百人
Give me an hour and I can put a hundred swords at your command.
请问我要这一百人做什么呢？
And what should I do with a hundred swords?
先发制人！趁今晚大家还在熟睡时
Strike! Tonight while the castle sleeps.
我们得把乔佛里从他母亲手里夺过来当筹码
We must get Joffrey away fro his mother and into our custody.
是不是守护者无关紧要 挟有国王才能号令全国
Protector of the Realm or no, he who holds the King holds the Kingdom.
而您每耽搁一秒 就是多给瑟曦一秒准备的时间
Every moment you delay gives Cersei another moment to prepare.
等劳勃一死 只怕对你我两人都为时已晚
By the time Robert dies, it will be too late for the both of us.
史坦尼斯对此会怎么说呢？
What about Stannis?
莫非您打算把七国从瑟曦魔掌下拯救出来 又拱手交给史坦尼斯？
Saving the Seven Kingdoms from Cersei and delivering them to Stannis?
您对“守护王国”的理解可真奇特
You have odd notions about protecting the realm.
史坦尼斯可是你的兄长
Stannis is your older brother.
我们所谈论的事与血统继承无关
This isn't about the bloody line of succession.
当年你们起兵推翻疯王 何曾考虑过继承权？
That didn't matter when you rebelled against the Mad King.
你现在又何苦斤斤计较？
It shouldn't matter now.
怎样做对国家最有利？
What's best for the Kingdoms?
怎样做才对得起老百姓？
What's best for the people we rule?
我们都清楚史坦尼斯是什么德行
We all know what Stannis is.
没人爱戴他 也不会有人真正追随他
He inspires no love or loyalty.
他不是当国王的料
He's not a King.
而我是
I am.
史坦尼斯是一位优秀的指挥官
Stannis is a commander.
他两度担任大军统帅
He's led men into war twice.
他摧毁过葛雷乔伊的舰队...
He destroyed the Greyjoy fleet--
没错 每个人都知道 他很会打仗...
Yes, he's a good soldier. Everyone knows that.
就和劳勃一样
So was Robert.
可见识了劳勃的所做所为之后
Tell me something:
你还相信会打仗等于能治国吗？
Do you still believe good soldiers make good kings?
我不会在劳勃生命的最后时刻
I will not dishonor Robert's last hours
在朝堂里杀人流血
by shedding blood in his halls
犯下把惊慌失措的孩子从睡梦中强行拉走的罪行
and dragging frightened children from their beds.
今晚你就坐船去龙石船
You will sail to dragonstone tonight.
托马德
史塔克家族的侍卫
把这封信当面交给史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩大人
You will place this in the hand of Stannis Baratheon.
记住 不管是他的总管
Not his steward,
侍卫队长
not his Captain of the guard,
或他的夫人都不行
and not his wife.
一定要交给史坦尼斯本人
Only Stannis himself.
遵命 大人
Yes, My Lord.
去吧
Now leave us.
全境守护者大人
My Lord protector.
国王没有亲生儿子
The King has no trueborn sons.
乔佛里和托曼
Joffrey and Tommen
是詹姆·兰尼斯特的私生子
are Jaime Lannister's bastards.
- 所以国王死后... - 王位应传给他二弟
- So when the King dies-- - The throne passes to his brother
史坦尼斯大人
Lord Stannis.
看来是如此
So it would seem.
- 除非... - 没有“除非”！
- Unless-- - there is no "unless."
史坦尼斯是合法继承人 没有什么可以改变事实
He is the rightful heir. Nothing can change that.
但缺了你的协助 他得不到王位
And he cannot take the throne without your help.
如果你够聪明 就应该忽略他
You would be wise to deny it to him
确保乔佛里登基为王
and to make sure Joffrey succeeds.
你一点荣誉心都没有吗？
Do you have a shred of honor?
你既是首相 又是全境守护者
You are now Hand of the King and Protector of the Realm.
大权在握 只需伸手...
All of the power is yours. You need only
便可夺取天下
reach out and take it.
与兰尼斯特家和好
Make peace with the Lannisters.
释放小恶魔 把你女儿嫁给乔佛里
Release the Imp. Wed your daughter to Joffrey.
我们有足够的时间解决掉史坦尼斯
We have plenty of time to get rid of Stannis.
若是乔佛里登上王位后
And if Joffrey seems likely to cause problems when he
惹人厌
comes into his throne,
我们只需揭穿他的小秘密
we simply reveal his little secret
再把蓝礼大人送上台...
and seat Lord Renly there instead.
我们？
We?
您总需要别人来帮您分担重责大任罢
You'll need someone to share these burdens.
我跟您保证 我的价码绝对公道
I assure you-- my price would be modest.
你建议的可是叛国大罪
What you suggest is treason.
除非我们失败
Only if we lose.
你要我跟兰尼斯特家讲和...
Make peace with the Lannisters, you say...
他们派人杀我儿子
With the people who tried to murder my boy.
大人 只有和敌人才谈得上“讲和”二字
We only make peace with our enemies, My Lord.
您懂吗？
That's why it's called "making peace."
不 我不会这么做
No. I won't do it.
所以就是史坦尼斯和战争？
So it will be Stannis and war?
我别无选择
There is no other choice.
史坦尼斯是继承人
He is the heir.
那您找我有何贵干？
So why did you call me here?
既然不为了我的智慧
Not for my wisdom, clearly.
你答应过凯特琳会帮忙
You promised Catelyn you would help me.
王后身边有十来位骑士和上百名侍卫
The Queen has a dozen knights and a hundred men-at-arms--
足够对付我留在身边的护卫
enough to overwhelm what remains of my household guard.
我需要金袍子
I need the gold cloaks.
都城守卫队一共有两千人
The City Watch is 2,000 strong
他们宣誓以国王之名维护和平
and sworn to defend the King's peace.
瞧你这个样子
Look at you.
你知道要请我做什么
You know what you want me to do,
更明白这件事势在必行
you know it has to be done,
可它一点也不名誉 所以话哽在你喉咙里说不出来
but it's not honorable so the words stick in your throat.
当王后立了一个国王
When the Queen proclaims one King
首相却立了另一个
and the Hand proclaims another,
请问金袍子要以谁之名维护和平哩？
whose peace do the Gold Cloaks protect?
他们会支持谁？
Who do they follow?
付钱的人
The man who pays them.
倾听我的誓言 做我的见证
Hear my words and bear witness to my vow.
长夜将至 我从今开始守望
Night gathers and now my watch begins.
至死方休
It shall not end until my death.
我将不娶妻
I shall take no wife,
不封地 不生子
hold no lands, father no children.
我将不戴宝冠 不争荣宠
I shall wear no crowns and win no glory.
波文·马尔锡
守夜人的首席事务官
我将尽忠职守 生死于斯
I shall live and die at my post.
我是黑暗中的利剑
I am the sword in the darkness.
长城上的守卫
I am the watcher on the walls.
守护王国的坚盾
I am the shield that guards the realms of men.
我将生命与荣耀献给守夜人
I pledge my li and honor to The Night's Watch,
今夜如此 夜夜皆然
for this night and all the nights to come.
你们跪下时 尚为孩童
You knelt as boys.
起来吧 守夜人的汉子
Rise now as men of The Night's Watch.
恭喜 恭喜
Well done. Well done.
他咬了什么？
What's he got there?
白灵 来我这儿 把东西带过来
To me, ghost. Bring it here.
诸神慈悲！
Gods be good!
他们会怎么处置他？
What will they do to him?
当卡拉萨开拔时 他会被栓在马后面
When the Khalasar rides, he'll be leashed to a saddle,
跟着马群无休止的奔跑
forced to run behind the horses for as long as he can.
如果他摔倒呢？
And when he falls?
我见过的人最多坚持九里
I saw a man last nine miles once.
劳勃国王还在追杀我
King Robert still wants me dead.
这个下毒的是第一个 但绝不会是最后一个
This poisoner was the first. He won't be the last.
我以为我哥哥死了
I thought he'd leave me alone--
他就会放过我
now that my brother is gone.
他永远也不会放过你
He will never leave you alone.
哪怕你逃到阴影笼罩的亚夏 他的刺客也会尾随而至
If you ride to darkest Asshai, his assassins will follow you.
即便你远航至蛇蜥群岛
If you sailed all the way to the Basilisk Isles,
他的探子也会查出你的去向
his spies would tell him.
他不会半途而废
He will never abandon the hunt.
因为你是坦格利安家的人 最后的坦格利安
You're a Targaryen-- the last Targaryen.
你的儿子有真龙血脉
Your son will have Targaryen blood
还有四万骑马战士的拥护
with 40,000 riders behind him.
他绝不能伤到我儿子
He will not have my son.
他也绝不能伤到你 卡丽熙
He will not have you either, Khaleesi.
Zhey jalan atthirari anni.
我生命中的月亮
Moon of my live.
Hash azisi?
你没受伤吧？
Are you hurt?
Jora Andahli
安达尔人乔拉
Jorah the Andal
okki zhille hrazef fin allayafa shafka
我听说了你的作为
I heard what you did
drogikhoon anni.Me shafki.
任意挑选一匹马 它是你的了
choose any horse you wish [from my herd]. It's yours.
Anha asshilak jin azh shafkea haji rekoon et shafka.
这是我送你的礼物
I make this gift to you for what you did.
Ma rizhaan anni, vezh fin asaja rhaesheseres,
至于我的儿子 骑着世界的骏马
And to my son, the stallion who will mount the world,
maan anha valloshak azh akka.
我也要送他一件礼物
I will also pledge a gift.
Maan anha vazhak jin ador shiqethi
我要送他铁椅子……
I will give him the iron chair
finaan neva ave maisi mae.
那张他母亲的父亲坐过的铁椅子
that his mothers father sat upon.
Anha vazhak maan Rhaeshis Andahli.
我要送他七大王国
I will give The Lands of the Andals.
Anha,zhey Drogo,atak jin.
我 卓戈 要做这件事
I, Drogo, will do this.
Anha vidrik khalasares anni jim,
我要带着我的卡拉萨向西走到世界尽头
I will take my khalasar west to where the world ends
finaan nakhoe rhaesheser,
骑着木马横渡黑色咸水
and ride wooden horses across the black salt sea
majin adothrak hrazef ido yomme Havazzhifi Kazga ven et vo khal avvos.
做出古往今来其他卡奥从来没有做过的事
as no khal has done before.
Anha vaddrivak mahrazhis fini ondee
我要杀死穿铁衣服的人
I will kill the men in iron suits
khogar shiqethi ma vohharak okrenegwin mori.
拆了他们的石头房子
and tear down their stone houses.
Anha aqorisok chiories mori,
我要强奸他们的女人
I will rape their women,
vazzafrok yal mori,
抓他们的小孩来作奴隶
take their children as slaves
ma afichak vojjor samva Vaesaan Dothrak.
把他们没有用的神像带回维斯·多斯拉克
and bring their broken gods back to Vaes Dothrak.
Ki jini anha astak asqoy,
我在此发誓
This i vow
anha, Drogo ki Bharbosi.
我 拔尔勃之子卓戈
Drogo son of Bharbo.
Ki jini anha astak asqoy hatif Maisi Krazaaji kash shieraki vitihiri asavvasoon.
在圣母山前发誓
I swear before the mother of mountains
Asavvasoon!
以天上群星为证
as the stars look down in witness.
Asavvasoon!
以天上群星为证
As the stars look down in witness.
史塔克大人！
Lord Stark!
- 站住！ - 不 没关系
- Stop! - No, all right.
没关系 让他过来
It's all right. Let him through.
史塔克大人 乔佛里国王和太后摄政王陛下
Lord Stark, King Joffrey and the Queen Regent
要您立刻到王座厅觐见
request your presence in the Throne Room.
乔佛里国王？
King Joffrey?
劳勃国王陛下走了
King Robert is gone.
愿天上诸神让他安息
The Gods give him rest.
都办妥了 都城守备队听从您调遣
All is accomplished. The City Watch is yours.
很好
Good.
蓝礼大人呢？
Is Lord Renly joining us?
恐怕蓝礼大人已经出城了
I fear Lord Renly has left the city.
天亮前一个小时
He rode through the old gate
他自旧城门离开
an hour before dawn
随行的有洛拉斯·提利尔爵士和五十名随从
with Ser Loras Tyrell and some 50 retainers.
据最新情报 他们正快马加鞭往南赶
Last seen galloping South in some haste.
我们是您坚实的后盾 史塔克大人
We stand behind you, Lord Stark.
恭迎
All hail his Grace,
安达尔人和先民的国王
Joffrey of Houses Baratheon and Lannister,
七国统治者
the first of his name,
暨全境守护者
King of the Andals and the First Men,
拜拉席恩家族与兰尼斯特家族的
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms
乔佛里一世陛下
and Protector of the Realm.
我命令御前会议
I command the council to make all necessary arrangements
全速准备我的加冕仪式
for my coronation.
我希望在两周内完成加冕
I wish to be crowned within the fortnight.
今天我要接受朝廷重臣的
Today I shall accept oaths of fealty
宣誓效命
from my loyal councilors.
巴利斯坦爵士
Ser Barristan,
我相信在场无人可以置疑您的荣誉
I believe no man here could ever question your honor.
这是劳勃国王的印信 未经拆封
King Robert's seal-- unbroken.
……任命艾德·史塔克公爵
"Lord Eddard Stark is herein named
为摄政王及全境守护者
Protector of the Realm,
代吾统理国事
to rule as Regent
俟吾之合法继承人成年为止
until the heir come of age."
巴利斯坦爵士 我可以看看吗？
May I see that letter, Ser Barristan?
全境守护者
Protector of the realm.
史塔克大人 你想拿这当挡箭牌吗？
Is this meant to be your shield, Lord Stark?
就凭区区一张纸？
A piece of paper?
- 那是国王的遗嘱啊 - 我们有了新国王
- Those were the King's words. - We have a new King now.
艾德大人 上次见面 你给了我一些建议
Lord Eddard, when we last spoke you offered me some counsel.
现在也让我回个礼
Allow me to return the courtesy.
跪下 大人
Bend the knee, My Lord.
只要您跪下宣誓效忠我儿子
Bend the knee and swear loyalty to my son--
我们就准许你回到那片你称之为家的灰色荒原
and we shall allow you to live out your days
安享晚年
in the gray waste you call home.
你儿子无权继承王位
Your son has no claim to the throne.
你骗人！
Liar!
史塔克大人 你这是自寻死路
You condemn yourself with your own mouth, Lord Stark.
巴利斯坦爵士 拿下这个叛徒
Ser Barristan, seize this traitor.
巴利斯坦爵士是位正直忠诚的人 别伤害他
Ser Barristan is a good man, a loyal man. Do him no harm.
你以为巴利斯坦爵士孤军奋战吗？
You think he stands alone?
杀了他！把他们通通杀掉！我命令你们！
Kill him! Kill all of them, I command it!
司令！
Commander,
杰诺斯·史林特
都城守备队队长
请您暂时拘捕王后和她的孩子
take the Queen and her children into custody.
将他们送回王家居室
Escort them back to the royal apartments
并派人加以看守
and keep them there, under guard.
都城守备队！
Men of the Watch!
我不希望发生无谓的流血
I want no bloodshed.
叫你的手下放下武器
Tell your men to lay down their swords.
不需白白送命
No one needs to die.
动手！
Now!
我不是警告你别信任我的嘛
I did warn you not to trust me.